HARUN MOMANYI

CONTENT DEVELOPMENT & MARKETING STRATEGIST

DETAILS

EMAIL

harun@tranquilmediagroup.com

SKILLS

Digital Marketing

• • • • •

Social Media Marketing

• • • •

Content Marketing

• • • •

Interviewing

• • • •

SEO

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ

Digital Photography

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ

LANGUAGES

English

• • • • •

Swahili

• • • •

PROFILE

I am a highly experienced digital content creator, integrated marketing strategist, and media entrepreneur with over 7 years of experience in mainstream digital media, My wealth of skills include data-driven storytelling, market research, media relations, and content development. I have demonstrated well documented success in my previous roles, and a continuous learning attitude. I believe that I am the best candidate for this role at your company.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Founder & CEO, Tranquil Media Limited

Jun 2017 — Present

- · Manage the company's vision and mission on a day-to-day basis.
- Oversee the editorial direction of the flagship websites, careerfodder.com and fashiontoday.vip
- In charge of business development, and partnerships. Have collaborated with leading brands, including Uber Kenya, Kempinski Hotels, Bentley Nairobi, Crowne Plaza Hotels & Nyama Mama Delta on product/service reviews, events and launches.
- Overseeing monetization of the brand's digital assets with adtech, media buying and influencer marketing.
- Executing the brand strategy and ensuring it contributes towards company revenue targets.
- · Ensuring the company is tax-compliant.
- · Manage the team and onboard interns and independent contractors.

Contributor, Msafiri Magazine, Kenya Airways

Dec 2020 — Present

- · Created over 5 world-class cover stories for the reputable airline's magazine.
- Interviewed over 10 of Africa's top, award-winning musicians, covering Zambia, Cameroon, Nigeria, Senegal, Kenya, and Namibia for the Sept/Oct 2021 issue.
- Advised the publisher on editorial content themes, app improvements, and website traffic generation.
- Ensured that the commissioned content met global editorial standards, as millions of travelers read the magazine on a monthly basis.
- Interviewed 21 of Africa's most popular celebrities for the Dec 2020/Jan 2021 issue of the magazine. From a UK-based dancer to a TikTok star with over 1.5 million followers, the magazine generated impeccable buzz.
- Collaborated with my celebrity interviewees to promote the magazine on their social channels, with the most liked post garnering over 25,000 likes on Instagram.

Lifestyle Writer, African Vibes Magazine

Feb 2020 — Jul 2020

• Contributed to the Los Angeles - based publication, focusing on African entertainment, politics, and fashion.

- Managed the brand's ecommerce store and social media, with a 5% increase in Instagram growth rate.
- · Increased the fashion store's Instagram impressions by 2635%.
- · Increased the store's reach on Instagram by 868%.
- Interviewed top South African, Kenyan and Nigerian influencers for the publication's Afronista series.

Digital Journalist, Radio Africa Group

Dec 2014 — Aug 2018

- Wrote over 2,000 stories for the company's lifestyle websites, kiss100.co..ke, classic105.com, mpasho.co.ke and the-star.co.ke
- Wrote sponsored content articles and ran corresponding social media campaigns that brought in over \$50,000 in revenue monthly.
- Interviewed over 60 top African musicians, actors, influencers, CEOs, music video directors and brought in over 100,000 website views monthly.
- Served as an event photographer, covering high-profile events such as Fashion High Tea, Nairobi Fashion Week, Jumia Glamour Awards, Bingwa Music Awards and The Search music competition.
- · Produced a YouTube fashion show dubbed Fab Lab for Kiss 100 FM.
- Managed in-house influencer social media pages, with over a combined reach of over 24M monthly at the time.
- Contributed editorial suggestions in weekly meetings to improve the company's offerings.
- Was nominated for Forbes Africa 30Under30 and shortlisted for the BBC Komla Rumor Award in 2018 for my work as a digital journalist.

Editorial & Digital Assistant, Destination Magazine

Jun 2014 — Nov 2014

- Managed the publication's social media pages, with a peak 6M monthly reach during the World Cup.
- Transcribed audio for cover interviews with award-winning Hollywood stars, including Patrick Stewart, Malin Akerman, Tom Arnold, Robin Wright, and Matthew McConaughey.
- \cdot Updated the magazine website with 5 top global news stories daily.
- · Reviewed the magazine to ensure quality before packaging at the publisher.
- Came up with and actualized editorial suggestions, my favorite being a feature on renowned high-fashion model Malaika Firth.

EDUCATION

MBA Media Leadership candicate, University of Cumbria

Mar 2022 — Mar 2023

The MBA Media Leadership equips candidates with the knowledge and understanding required to analyze, direct and develop business operations in the modern media environment involving journalism, marketing, and public relations.

Product Marketing Core Certification, Product Marketing Alliance

Jul 2021 — Sep 2021

The product marketing industry's go-to certification. I have gained hands-on skills in research, pricing, OKRs, personas, positioning & messaging, Go-To-Market, communication, sales enablement, analytics and optimization. The course has been built by leading product marketers from Facebook, Google, Hubspot, Sage, Microsoft and other reputable brands.

Business Analytics, Udacity

Sep 2021 — Dec 2021

The course offers foundational data skills applicable to any industry. These include collecting and analyzing data, modeling business scenarios, and communicating findings with SQL, Excel, and Tableau.

Digital Marketing Leadership, AVADO Learning

Nov 2019 — Jun 2020

Squared Online is the award-winning digital marketing leadership course powered by AVADO, developed with Google. Grandaunts get a certificate endorsed by the IAB and the IPA, and accredited by the CPD – with skills highly sought after by brands, agencies and startups alike. I gained practical skills in customer centricity, data analytics and insights, digital transformation leadership, and digital channels and technologies.

Fashion Industry Essentials, Parsons School of Design

May 2016 — Jun 2017

Fashion program taught by reputable faculty from Parsons School of Design and leading fashion industry insiders from Condé Nast, Project Runway, Teen Vogue, Rebecca Minkoff and others. I gained practical skills in portfolio design, fashion production, marketing & PR, and photography.

COURSES

Inside LVMH, LVMH Moët Hennessy Louis Vuitton

Jun 2021 — Aug 2021

Content Marketing, Hubspot

Jul 2021 — Jul 2021

SEO, Hubspot

Jul 2021 — Jul 2021

Social Media Management, AgoraPulse

Jan 2020 — May 2020

REFERENCES

Azola Fali from The Room | African Leadership Group

afali@theroom.com

Kaitlyn Swist from The Room | African Leadership Group

kswist@theroom.com